// import { CATEGORYDATA } from "../Components/QuizCard/QuizCard";

import { QUIZCATEGORIES } from "./data.types";

export const data: QUIZCATEGORIES = {
  quizCategories: [
    {
      quizName: "Marvel Fanatic",
      description: "Are you a Marvel fan?If yes then don't miss this",
      questions: [
        {
          question:
            "IRON MAN 2: What fake name does Natasha use when she first meets Tony?",
          options: [
            "Natalie Rushman",
            "Natalia Romanoff",
            "Nicole Rohan",
            "Naya Rabe",
          ],
          correctOption: "Natalie Rushman",
        },
        {
          question:
            "THE AVENGERS: Natasha remarks to Clint that the Battle of New York is a lot like what?",
          options: [
            "Their time in Prague",
            "Their time in Sokovia",
            "Their time in Budapest",
            "Their time in Istanbul",
          ],
          correctOption: "Their time in Budapest",
        },
        {
          question:
            "THOR: THE DARK WORLD: Where do Sif and Volstagg hide the Reality Stone at the end of the movie?",
          options: [
            "On Vormir",
            "In a vault on Asgard",
            "Inside Sif's sword",
            "They give it to the Collector",
          ],
          correctOption: "They give it to the Collector",
        },
        {
          question:
            "CAPTAIN AMERICA: THE WINTER SOLDIER: What does the Winter Soldier say after Steve recognizes him for the first time?",
          options: [
            "Do i know you?",
            "Who the hell is Bucky?",
            "He's gone",
            "What did you say?",
          ],
          correctOption: "Who the hell is Bucky?",
        },
        {
          question:
            "GUARDIANS OF THE GALAXY: What were the three items Rocket claims he needs in order to escape the prison?",
          options: [
            "A security card, a fork, and an ankle monitor",
            "A pair of binoculars, a detonator, and a prosthetic leg",
            "A Security Band, a battery and a prosthetic leg",
            "A knife, cable wires, and Peter's mixtape",
          ],
          correctOption: "A Security Band, a battery and a prosthetic leg",
        },
        {
          question:
            "AVENGERS: AGE OF ULTRON: What word does Tony utter that makes Steve say, 'Language'?",
          options: ["Shit!", "Crap!", "Asshole!", "Idiot!"],
          correctOption: "Shit!",
        },
        {
          question:
            "ANT-MAN: What animal does Darren Cross unsuccessfully shrink?",
          options: ["Mouse", "Sheep", "Duck", "Hamster"],
          correctOption: "Sheep",
        },
        {
          question: `GUARDIANS OF THE GALAXY VOL. 2: Finish this line: "I'm _______, y'all!" `,
          options: ["Superman", "Peter Pan", "Underdog", "Marry Poppins"],
          correctOption: "Marry Poppins",
        },
        {
          question:
            "BLACK PANTHER: What do Killmonger and Klaue steal from the Museum of Great Britain?",
          options: [
            "Just vibranium",
            "Vibranium and a Mask",
            "A map of Wakanda",
            "A map of Wakanda and Vibranium",
          ],
          correctOption: "Vibranium and a Mask",
        },
        {
          question:
            "AVENGERS: INFINITY WAR: What elective class did Thor take on Asgard?",
          options: [
            "Learning to speak Groot",
            "Hammer making",
            "Learning to fly a space ship",
            "How to take care of snakes",
          ],
          correctOption: "Learning to speak Groot",
        },
      ],
    },
    {
      quizName: "Space Wanderer",
      description: "Hop in if Space fascinates you",
      questions: [
        {
          question: "Who invented the telescope?",
          options: ["Hypatia", "Johannes Kepler", "Hans Lippershey", "Galileo"],
          correctOption: "Hans Lippershey",
        },
        {
          question: "Which of these objects is the farthest from the Sun?",
          options: ["90377 Sedna", "Saturn", "Neptune", "Kuiper belt"],
          correctOption: "90377 Sedna",
        },
        {
          question: "What is the smallest planet in the solar system by mass?",
          options: ["Earth", "Mercury", "Mars", "Jupiter"],
          correctOption: "Mercury",
        },
        {
          question: "What is the visible part of the Sun called?",
          options: [
            "the atmosphere",
            "the photosphere",
            "the stratosphere",
            "the lithosphere",
          ],
          correctOption: "the photosphere",
        },
        {
          question: "What makes a planet a dwarf planet?",
          options: [
            "smell",
            "color",
            "size and shape",
            "distance from the Sun",
          ],
          correctOption: "size and shape",
        },
        {
          question: "What two motions do all planets have?",
          options: [
            "orbit and spin",
            "rock and roll",
            "twist and shout",
            "wiggle and wobble",
          ],
          correctOption: "orbit and spin",
        },
        {
          question: "When did the Space Age begin?",
          options: ["1957", "1941", "1969", "1999"],
          correctOption: "1957",
        },
        {
          question:
            "With which US spacecraft did Neil Armstrong and Edwin Aldrin, Jr. land on the moon?",
          options: ["Apollo 7", "Apollo 13", "Apollo 17", "Apollo 11"],
          correctOption: "Apollo 11",
        },
        {
          question: "Who was the first person to enter outer space twice?",
          options: [
            "Yuri Gagarin",
            "Scott Kelly",
            "Vladimir Komarov",
            "Christina Koch",
          ],
          correctOption: "Vladimir Komarov",
        },
        {
          question: "The atmosphere in Mars is mostly composed of:",
          options: ["Nitrogen", "Carbon dioxide", "Helium", "Oxygen"],
          correctOption: "Carbon dioxide",
        },
      ],
    },
    {
      quizName: "Science Buff",
      description: "Dwel into the world of Scientific marvels",
      questions: [
        {
          question:
            "In 1910 which French engineer and chemist found that passing electrical current through inert gases produced light and proceeded to develop the neon lamp?",
          options: [
            "Georges Claude",
            "Charles Janet",
            "Edward Adam",
            "René Jacques Lévy",
          ],
          correctOption: "Georges Claude",
        },
        {
          question: "Which of these chemical elements is heavier than iron?",
          options: ["Gold", "Pottasium", "Carbon", "manganese"],
          correctOption: "Gold",
        },
        {
          question:
            "A baby blue whale drinks this many liters of milk per day:",
          options: ["500", "190", "50", "170"],
          correctOption: "190",
        },
        {
          question: "Who invented the World Wide Web?",
          options: [
            "the Federal Communications Commission",
            "A laboratory in Switzerland",
            "Apple",
            "Microsoft",
          ],
          correctOption: "A laboratory in Switzerland",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which of the following technological developments came first?",
          options: ["teletype", "telephone", "telegraph", "telescope"],
          correctOption: "telescope",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Who developed the theory of the chemical reactivity of oxygen?",
          options: [
            "Antoine Lavoisier",
            "Louis Pasteur",
            "John Dalton",
            "Joseph Priestley",
          ],
          correctOption: " Antoine Lavoisier",
        },
        {
          question: "What kind of substance makes litmus paper turn blue?",
          options: ["Acid", "Salt", "Alkali", "Base"],
          correctOption: " Antoine Lavoisier",
        },
        {
          question: "Who discovered X-rays?",
          options: [
            "Raymond Gosling",
            "Wilhelm Röntgen",
            "Riccardo Giacconi",
            "Marie Curie",
          ],
          correctOption: "Wilhelm Röntgen",
        },
        {
          question: "Which of these chemicals help fruit to ripen?",
          options: ["Ethylene", "Methane", "Nitrogen oxide", "Carbon dioxide"],
          correctOption: "Ethylene",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The layer of the atmosphere in which weather occurs is called the:",
          options: ["Ionosphere", "Troposphere", "Mesosphere", "Stratosphere"],
          correctOption: " Troposphere",
        },
      ],
    },
    {
      quizName: "Aquatic Life",
      description: "Dive in deep to test yourself aboout what's in there",
      questions: [
        {
          question: "What is the largest fish in the world?",
          options: ["Whale shark", "Sperm whale", "Sailfish", "Blue whale"],
          correctOption: "Whale shark",
        },
        {
          question: "What shark can live in both freshwater and saltwater?",
          options: [
            "Blue shark",
            "Blacktip shark",
            "Great white shark",
            "Bull shark",
          ],
          correctOption: "Bull shark",
        },
        {
          question: "What is the fastest fish in the world?",
          options: ["Wahoo", "Sailfish", "Mako shark", "Yellowfin tuna"],
          correctOption: "Sailfish",
        },
        {
          question: "What is the tail fin of a fish called?",
          options: ["Dorsal fin", "Caudal fin", "Anal fin", "Pectoral fin"],
          correctOption: "Caudal fin",
        },
        {
          question: "What is a sharks skeleton made of?",
          options: ["Collagen", "Bone tissue", "Calcite", "Cartilage"],
          correctOption: "Cartilage",
        },
        {
          question: "Which invertebrate can change genders?",
          options: ["Oyster", "Blue crab", "Sand dollar", "Barnacle"],
          correctOption: "Oyster",
        },
        {
          question: "What is a mass of jellyfish floating together called?",
          options: ["Crash", "Smack", "Unkindness", "Murder"],
          correctOption: "Smack",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The exoskeleton of a crab is made primarily of what material?",
          options: ["Sclerotin", "Keratin", "Chitin", "Concrete"],
          correctOption: "Chitin",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What part of a fish may be found in lipsticks, nail polishes and mascara?",
          options: ["Fin tissue", "Bones", "Scales", "Skin"],
          correctOption: "Scales",
        },
        {
          question: "How does a sea cucumber defend itself?",
          options: [
            "Camouflage",
            "Hides in crevices",
            "Throws up",
            "Secretes ink",
          ],
          correctOption: "Throws up",
        },
      ],
    },
  ],
};
// console.log(data);
